Kwame Ampoma - Mensah

Senior Front-End Enginner

Mobile: +44 7535 316817 Email: kamensgh@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/kamensgh Website: https://kamensgh.com/

OBJECTIVE

I'm a Front-End engineer with over 7 years of experience in all aspects of front-end development but currently using React (NextJS) and React Native to deliver the best user-centered products. I'm good at working with different teams to solve problems and impact organizational outcomes positively.

Skills

JavaScript NextJS

Typescript React - Native

NodeJS Storybook

State Management Redux

Context

CSS Frameworks Tailwind

Bootstrap

Database MongoDB

Firebase

Authentication NextAuth, KeyCloak

API RESTful

CI/CD Git

Others Web Development

Team player

UI/UX Azure

EDUCATION

Methodist University College

Accra - Ghana

BSc Degree in Information Technology

Sept 2009 - Sept 2014

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Front-End Developer

May 2018 - Till Date

Hubtel limited

- Led a development team of four front-end engineers to integrate RESTful APIs and build a
 consumer and vendor portal for the Electricity Company of Ghana leveraging Next.js
 server-side rendering to enhance security, performance and SEO. This portal facilitated
 secure power sales to citizens and efficiently managed issue reporting for over 1 million daily
 active users and a workforce of over 10,000 staff, demonstrating Next.js's capability to
 handle large-scale, high-performance applications.
- Collaborated with the design team to establish a brand guide and design system ensuring a
 consistent look and feel across all platforms. This initiative reduced development time by
 30% through the use of React, NPM and Storybook.js for reusable components.
- Rebuilt our main e-commerce web application from PHP to Vue.js, leveraging Vue's reactive
 data binding, component-based architecture, and client-side rendering. This transition
 aimed to increase the number of items a user could see per session and enhance their
 overall experience. As a result, we achieved a 40% increase in sales.
- Worked closely with product managers to maximize value delivery by employing Agile and Scrum methodologies. This approach kept projects on track, prioritized tasks effectively, and boosted team productivity and efficiency.
- Led daily stand-ups to ensure team efficiency and provide visibility into project statuses, facilitating more effective planning and strategy adjustments based on concrete information.
- Collaborated with the Quality Assurance team to test new products and features, addressing any issues within 48 hours. This commitment resulted in 100% bug-free development.
- Integrated SonarQube into our Azure builds for continuous code quality inspection, ensuring early detection and resolution of bugs.

Front-End Engineer

May 2023 - Nov 2023

RightCom

- Developed digital signage software with content, screen, and schedule management functionalities, designed for companies like banks and telecommunications offices to share content on screens with customers across various locations.
- Implemented Keycloak authentication as the primary login method for all RightCom applications using ReactJS, enhancing security and user management.
- Rewrote HTML to meet industry and company standards for SEO and accessibility, driving a 100% increase in users by achieving first-page Google search results.

Front-End Engineer

June 2016 - May 2017

Cobalt Partners

- Translated UX wireframes into design-perfect, responsive, interactive web pages, using HTML/CSS and Bootstrap.
- Improved website load time through optimization techniques including code refactoring, image compression, and caching, significantly enhancing user experience.
- Built the company website using HTML and CSS, which was transformed into a WordPress platform to facilitate easy content management.